Rafat Ramoni

Junior Full Stack Developer

Rafatramoni15@gmail.com • +353899859731 • Ireland

GitHub: https://github.com/Rafz9Abz9 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafat-ramoni/

Executive Summary

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. I have 4+ years' experience in Customer Service. I am a valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving ability. I am eager to enter the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

Education

February 2023–February 2024 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute, Dublin

(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

September 2020—June 2022 Masters in Medicine

Dnipro Medical Institute, Ukraine. (Disrupted due to war in Ukraine)

Technical Skillset

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Databases: MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Portfolio projects

1. VitaXtreme – Website that promotes hair and beard treatment oil for users.

Technologies Used – HTML and CSS. GitHub - https://github.com/Rafz9Abz9/VitaXtreme

2. **Islamic-App** – Quiz website that tests users on their Islamic knowledge. **Technologies Used** - HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. **GitHub** - https://github.com/Rafz9Abz9/Islamic-App

3. Tic-tac-toe – This is a game created for users. One player is 'X' and the computer is 'O'. The players will take turns putting their marks in empty squares and the first player to ger 3 of their marks in a row (up, down, across, or diagonally).

Technologies Used – HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. GitHub - https://github.com/Rafz9Abz9/tictactoe

4. ABZRECIPE - Recipe website that introduces a world of culinary creativity, where you can explore, create, and savor delicious dishes from every corner of the globe.

Technologies Used – HTML and CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB. **GitHub - https://github.com/Rafz9Abz9/ABZRECIPE**

5. Essence – Essence: Your premier destination for premium self-care essentials. Simplify your routine with our curated selections covering hair, baby, skin, and men's care.

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe. **GitHub** - https://github.com/Rafz9Abz9/Essence

Work Experience

September 2022—October 2022 Customer Service Advisor - Abtran
(Remote - Cork) - Short employment to resume school.

- Provide relevant advice to customers primarily by phone and email.
- Effectively managing a database through accurate and efficient data entry.
- Adhering strictly to data protection and confidentiality laws.

January 2022—February 2022 Patient Scheduling Representative - RelateCare (Remote – Waterford) – Short employment to resume school.

- Address patient scheduling needs via inbound calls.
- Accurate data entry of patient's information to various systems.
- Verify and review patients and families' insurance coverage and benefit eligibility.

December 2019—August 2021 Healthcare Assistant – Bluebird Care (Kilkenny)

- Assisting clients with completing basic tasks such as going to the bathroom.
- Serving clients their meals and assisting them with eating and drinking.
- Taking them for a walk as a form of exercise.

Certifications

• Diploma certificate from Code Institute for completion of Full-Stack Software Development course.

Additional Information/Interests

- Participated in the Women Who Code mentor meeting and completed a challenge, awaiting my badge of completion. Also attend networking events.
- Completing the core curriculums on freeCodeCamp will obtain certificate after completion.
- Completing Python course on Great Learning will obtain certificate after completion.
- Completion of a Diploma in Introduction to Nursing at Marino College of Further Education in Dublin from September 2019 to June 2020.
- Completion of 1st year bachelor's in biotechnology at Athlone Institute of Technology, Athlone from September 2018 to May 2019 (left to pursue a degree in Medicine).
- Completion of Junior and Leaving Certificate at Loreto Secondary School in Kilkenny, Ireland from January 2013 to January 2018.